I don't need parents.
Humans are all alone.
They're not connected
to anyone at all.
How did it go?
Lain's acting funny.
It's nothing new, but still...
No, it's perfectly normal.
Huh? What're you talking about?
Mika, watch your tone
with your father.
Is she right?
Yes.
Shit! Shit!
Shit!
What do you want?!
What's going on?!
Shit!
SHIT!
Gotcha.
We have homeroom next hour, right?
Is that lucky, or what?
Don't you think it's strange that
they called a special staff meeting?
Do you think it's true, then?
What?
They say a high school
senior committed suicide.
S-Suicide?
It's not just at our school, either.
Somebody jumped off the roof of their
apartment building a while ago, too.
Hey, Lain.
Sorry. What is it?
I guess Lain wouldn't
know anything about it...
The suicide, you mean?
You know about that?
Really?
I've just heard a little
about it, that's all.
Where?
The Wired.
Right, you must've gotten the
hang of your new Navi by now.
You'll have to show
it to me sometime.
Sure. But I'm modifying
it a little right now.
Modifying it? I didn't know
you were into that hacky stuff.
You know, you've changed lately.
Really? You think so?
She has?
Yeah. I can't put my finger on it.
So, what sort of rumors have
you heard in the Wired?
Well... That's it's
some kind of game.
A game? A network game, you mean?
I don't really know.
I don't play those.
But they say that all the dead
kids were hooked on it.
Guys sure like that stuff...
A game, huh? But why?
I...
Hey, don't wolf down food
like that! You'll choke!
I'm okay.
You mind if I go home'?
Hey, you don't need to ask
our permission or anything.
You have plans?
I want to get home and put
my Navi back together.
It's still in bits and pieces.
You prefer a machine
to your friends, huh?
Cut it out, Juri!
Don't talk like that!
I'm not accusing her of anything.
Once you're done, you'll
have to show us, Lain.
Sure.
Sorry.
She has changed.
I'm sorry!
Here.
No, it was my fault.
Sorry!
Log in. Lain.
Authorized.
Mail.
Voice mail.
Hello, Lain.
I couldn't figure out the answer
to your question by myself,
so I asked a colleague
at the lab about it.
If that really is a Psyche
processor that you have,
then you should probably set the
oscillation to "variable" like you thought.
Navi motherboards are designed
to work with just about anything,
but you might run
into some glitches.
Good luck.
If you need anything
else, just ask.
JJ!
Yeah?
You know anything about that net
game that all the kids are playing?
Oh, you mean Phantoma?
Forget about it. An adult like
you wouldn't be into that.
Right, Lain?
No way...
Damn, are my ears playing
tricks on me already?
I... I quit already!
Leave me out of it!
This isn't the Wired!
Why? Why is this happening?!
Wait, don't run.
Who are you?!
Are you a PK, too? Help me!
I can't go where you are.
What's going on?!
Stop screwing around!
Bullet charge! Gauge 5!
Die!
I was scared, that's all.
I didn't know it was just a
little girl. It's not my fault.
I didn't even know her.
Phantoma is a game with a
dedicated client application...
...that lets you fight in the Wired.
I downloaded the app from an illegal
server to play it a little while ago.
For us, it had a dungeon-style
action game interface,
but I guess it had
somehow gotten linked...
to a tag game played
by kindergartners.
You have mail.
Open it.
Hey, Lain. I didn't know you
were into stuff like Phantoma.
I checked around, but
didn't find out much.
Anyway, the basic game isn't
all that unusual in the Wired,
so my guess is that
they just modified that.
The problem is the part that lets
the programs connect to each other.
It looks like there's some kind
of weird hole in the protocol.
My buddies and I think that this
may be the work of the Knights, too.
Knights...
Lain?
Looks like you and the Wired are
getting along just fine now.
Yeah.
Let me give you one little warning.
Huh?
When it's all said and
done, the Wired...
...is just a medium for communication
and the transfer of information.
You mustn't confuse it
with the real world.
Do you understand what
I'm warning you about?
You're wrong.
Huh?
The border between the
two isn't all that clear.
I'll be able to enter it soon.
In full range. Full motion.
I'll translate myself into it.
Even with a top of the line
civilian Navi, you couldn't...
I can do it. I've modified mine.
A Psyche processor, huh?
But...
Don't worry. I'm still me.
Sometimes I wonder.
I waited for you for hours!
Why? Why didn't you come?!
Damn you! Damn you! Damn you!
Damn you!
This mail is a
message of happiness!
By receiving this, you'll be
happier than anyone else!
In other words, the Knights
do not physically exist,
but are rather thought itself
that occurs within the Wired.
They can be thought of as a religion
that is spreading through the Wired.
Would you go out with me?
If you already have a
boyfriend, I apologize.
If you love him, I'll
give up on you. But if...
Please browse code
J946@5488AA97464.
Whoever gets this mail, please
help me, whoever you are.
You may not believe this,
but I'm always being followed.
Lain, why won't you come here?
Go away.
Go away!
Intruder interrupted.
I thought I was innocent,
but I'm being punished.
I didn't start this, but I
have to finish it somehow.
I can't say I didn't know about it,
but I don't remember taking part in it.
I get the feeling my
freedom cost me dearly,
but I don't remember
selling my soul cheaply.
Hey, hey!
Until I die and say goodbye...
...no one will ever catch me.
You probably don't know
the eternal outlaws...
...who wander the distant night.