I thought I was innocent,
but I'm being punished.
I didn't start this, but I
have to finish it somehow.
I can't say I didn't know about it,
but I don't remember taking part in it.
I get the feeling my
freedom cost me dearly,
but I don't remember
selling my soul cheaply.
Hey. hey!
Until I die and say goodbye...
...I"IO one can catch me.
You probably don't know
the eternal outlaws...
...who wander the distant night.
I... I'm confused again.
Am I here? Or am I there?
Over there, I'm everywhere.
I know that.
I'm connected there, after all.
Right?
But where is the real me?
Oh, right... There is no real me.
I only exist inside those people
who are aware of my existence.
But this me that's
talking right now...
It's me, isn't it?
This me that's talking...
This me... Who is it?
Arisu!
A body doesn't mean
anything to you, right?
Arisu...
No!
I mess up everything I try
to do for you, huh, Arisu?
Honest, I...
Arisu!
I'm sorry...
Arisu, I'm sorry...
I'm done.
Hey, you didn't clean your plate.
She says she's on a diet.
Tell the whole world, why don't you?
Oh, I might get a package
today. It's C.O. D.
If it comes, pay for it, okay?
Computer parts again?
Hey...
Yes?
No, it's nothing.
Arisu!
Arisu! We're going out tonight, right?
Cyberia! Cyberia!
Oh. Sure, why not?
I'd better mail her, then.
Arisu? Mail who?
Oh, don't tell me you want
her to come along again...
u Her"?
Chisa?
Yeah. Chisa Yomoda.
Arisu, you talked us into
taking her to Cyberia once,
but it's like she just didn't care.
Inviting her is pointless.
- Oh, I get it...
- Huh?
It's nothing.
I just thought of something strange.
Something strange?
If you don't remember something,
it never happened.
Don't remember?
If you aren't remembered,
you never existed.
Who are you talking about?
Like I said. Nobody.
C'mon, we'd better hit the books.
Arisu!
Go!
Man, I gotta do it again?
C'mon, one more time!
Hurry UP!
Wait for me!
You're such a sucker!
Mail?
What is it?
Who's that girl?!
I don't know.
Now what?
Hey, nice machine!
Mine's pretty tricked out, too.
C'mon! Hurry!
C'mon! C'mon!
Mom's waiting!
Okay, okay... 'Bye.
Let's go!
Wait! Shoot for it again!
Hurry up, Taro!
No fair! Shoot for it again!
I'll quit. I'll quit that dump.
The crap they make me do...
They all underestimate me...
Oh, well.
I'm gonna quit... I'm gonna quit!
I'm gonna quit!
I'm gonna quit today for sure!
Is that true?
Why are you crying?
Because you deleted yourself
from everyone's memory?
But isn't that what you wanted?
Yes, but...
No one is dying, and
no one is being hurt.
And no one hates you.
Yes, but...
Dead people's information isn't
leaking out of the Wired anymore.
So Lain doesn't need to
be anywhere anymore.
This is what you wanted, isn't it?
You sound just like him.
Him?
That man never existed now.
Even if he does, he won't get any
ideas into his head about being God.
I'm nowhere now...
If I'm nowhere, who am I?
Where am I?
You yourself said it.
The Wired isn't an upper
layer of the real world.
That's what that man
was mistaken about.
A network is a field to
pass along information.
Information doesn't
stand still there.
Information functions by
always being in motion.
Really?
People's memories aren’t just personal
or one part of the history of humanity.
No, not even the
shared unconscious.
Do you think that humans could
create something that could store...
"memory that's that vast?
The Wired was just connected
to something else...
But where was it connected to?
Do people really need to know that?
Look at how far they've
come without knowing.
The human world creates and
prays to its various gods,
and humans convince themselves,
"This is how the world is."
I don't like how you're saying this.
Either way, it's Lain
that's saying it. Me.
You understand that, right?
Oh, right... Lain was
never a person, was she?
Lain is omnipresent,
existing everywhere.
Lain watches quietly.
Right, Lain is God!
No...
You're wrong!
It'd be so much easier
if you became God.
I think it'd be a lot
easier than being a human.
You wouldn't have to do anything.
just stand there and watch.
No one would look down on Lain.
No one would hate Lain.
That's...
Hey, Lain... Let's start everything
over again from the beginning!
I mean,you did go and
reset everything, after all...
Stop it!
Then what are you, Lain?
I...
Where am I?
Come, Lain.
Dad?
You don't need to wear
that anymore, Lain.
Dad, do you know?
What?
I... Everyone, I...
You love them?
Isn't that right?
Lain, I'll make us some
nice tea next time.
Hey, with some madeleines!
Definitely. They're great!
So memories aren't only
of the past, are they?
They can be of right now,
or even of tomorrow...
Unbelievable!
Isn't it? But hang on a second...
I listened to what you had to say.
Very patiently, I might add.
I get to pick the curtains
for the bedroom, right?
Yes, ma'am.
Anything you say.
All right, then.
That's a good student.
Something wrong?
No.
Sorry, could you wait here a minute?
Hey, what're you--
Hello.
Have we met before?
We have, haven't we?
Did you go to the school I
was a student teacher at?
No, that can't be it...
Let me think...
Pleased to meet you.
Huh?
We haven't met before.
Oh. Well, I'm pleased
to meet you, then.
I'm Arisu.
Strange name, huh? I'm kind
of embarrassed about it.
What's yours?
Lain.
Lain...?
- A friend of yours?
- No, I thought she was someone else.
Well, goodbye, Lain.
Maybe we'll run into
each other again someday.
'Bye.
'Bye, Lain.
You're right. We can
see each other anytime.
I'm here, so I'll be
with you forever.
I thought I was innocent,
but I'm being punished.
I didn't start this, but I
have to finish it somehow.
I can't say I didn't know about it,
but I don't remember taking part in it.
I get the feeling my
freedom cost me dearly,
but I don't remember
selling my soul cheaply.
Hey. hey!
Until I die and say goodbye...
...no one can catch me.
You probably don't know
the eternal outlaws...