Oh, okay...
So that's how it works.
I had no idea the
world was this simple.
I always thought the world was
such a big and scary place,
but once you figure it
out, it's all so easy.
See? I told you it would be.
That's terrible, Lain!
I can't believe you just said that!
Lain...
I know, but it's true!
That's the first I've heard of it!
What does it mean?
Acting all high and
mighty again, huh, Lain?
That reminds me, Juri.
What?
But that's...
But that's--
Unbelievable...
Aw, c'mon...!
People only have substance
within the memories of others.
That's why there were
all kinds of me's.
There weren't a lot of me's,
I was just inside all sorts
of people, that's all.
Really... No kidding?
Come on, Taro, who
are you talking to?
W-What's up?
You know, I...
I kissed an angel.
Taro...
Lain...
Protocol Seven is expected to allow
the seamless sharing of information...
...between the Wired
and the real world.
And now, the following message...
Let's all love Lain!
All the functions of the human
body, without exception,
...can be put into words and
described in materialistic terms.
The body is nothing but a machine.
If the physical limitations of the
body restrict mankind's evolution,
it would be as if the fall of
the species called "man"...
...had already been decided by
a God that doesn't even exist.
The information etched inside
humans isn't only that which...
...they themselves have
acquired as individuals.
This species called man is
connected to his predecessors,
and information has
accumulated within him.
If that information isn't shared,
it's meaningless. Mere data.
Mankind can evolve.
Evolve by their own power.
But to do that, they must
first know what they truly are.
What do you think you are?
Originally, people were
connected to each other.
All I've done is to make
things as they once were.
That's what you have done, Lain.
So you can do anything you want.
I thought you quit smoking.
Why is this happening? We did
exactly what we were told to do!
It means that our client wasn't
the only one who thought that...
...those computer geeks playing
"secret society" would be trouble.
What do you mean?
Our client was in
contact with Masami Eiri.
No, maybe Eiri was behind it all.
Enough about Eiri, okay?
The guy's dead.
He's not dead.
Whether he had a body
or not never mattered.
It never mattered.
Are you serious?
Payment for services rendered, huh?
You've been using us, haven? you?!
Interpret it any way you like.
You want us to leave town,
huh?And go where?
I suppose a place with no power lines
that isn't covered by a satellite.
There's no place like that
on Earth, and you know it!
If you're going to run, you'll
have to find a place like that.
What's going to happen?
What are you planning to do...
...by connecting the Wired to the
real world without any devices?
Something wonderful
is going to happen.
I'm looking forward
to it. Aren't you?
What the-?
What's wrong?!
What are you seeing?!
Hey!
lwakura
Lain?
No...!
This is Lain's room?
Lain?
L-Lain!
A... risu?
What did you do?
Nothing.
I've just been watching.
Watching what?
I... I thought I had gone crazy.
But I didn't!
Lain! Why did you leave only me?
Why did you only leave
my memories alone?
Why do I always have to remember
all those horrible things?!
Do you hate me that much, Lain?
I... I can't take this!
No... You've got it all wrong, Arisu.
I didn't want to hurt you.
Liar! Look at what you've done!
But you’re okay, aren't you, Arisu?
You were my friend, even without
connecting with me, Arisu.
What are you saying?
You're my only friend, Arisu.
Even without connecting with me.
"Connecting"? W-What do you mean?
Connecting to me... And everyone...
S-Stop!
I love you, Arisu.
Do you know what you're saying, Lain?
Humans were originally connected
at an unconscious level.
I reconnected them, that's all.
Lain, you...?
I don't do anything.
It doesn't matter which is real,
this side or the other...
I was in both.
I'm a program designed
to destroy the barrier...
...between the Wired
and the real world.
You're a program, Lain...?
You and everyone else, Arisu,
you’re just applications.
The truth is, you
don't need bodies.
You're wrong.
I don't really understand what you're
saying, but I think you're wrong.
Your body's cold, but
you're alive, Lain.
Mine, too. See?
See? My heart...
...it's beating.
Beating... Beating...
But why? Why's it beating like that?
Because I'm scared.
It's pounding because I'm scared.
But you're smiling, Arisu.
Yeah, I guess I am. But I'm scared.
I've always been scared.
I wonder why?
Because she's afraid
of losing her body.
All sensations are caused
by impulses in the brain.
You just need to block
the unpleasant impulses.
Select only the happy, pleasant ones.
Really?
Lain? Who are you talking to?
If you really love her, why
don't you connect with her?
I'm not sure.
Lain? Who are you talking to?
Lain!
You must have a bug.
Very well. I'll take my time and
give you a thorough debugging.
Come, Lain.
What I don't understand is you, God.
Y-You're... talking to God?
What don't you understand, Lain?
What you did was to remove
devices from the Wired.
Phones... Television...
The network...
Without those, you couldn't
have done anything.
Yes. Those are things which
accompanied human evolution.
Humans who are further
evolved than others...
...have a right to
greater abilities.
Who gave you those rights?
The program that inserted
code synched to the Earth's...
...characteristic frequency into
the Protocol Seven code,
which would raise the collective
unconscious to the conscious level.
Did you really come up
with the idea by yourself?
What are you getting at?
No, it can't be... It can't be!
Are you telling me that
there really is a God?!
It doesn't matter. With no
body, you can't understand.
It's a lie! I... I'm Omnipotent!
I gave you a body here
in the real world!
You were omnipresent, scattered
through the Wired! I gave you an ego!
You mean to say-
lf that's true of me,
what about you?
I'm different! I--
The Wired isn't an upper
layer of the real world.
What do you mean?
Inside the Wired,
you were God, all right.
But what about before
the Wired was created?
You’re just an acting God,
standing in for someone...
...who was waiting for the Wired
to reach its current state.
An "acting” God?!
That can't be!
Arisu!
A body doesn't mean
anything to you, right?
No!
I thought I was innocent,
but I'm being punished.
I didn't start this, but I
have to finish it somehow.
I can't say I didn't know about it,
but I don't remember taking part in it.
I get the feeling my
freedom cost me dearly,
but I don't remember
selling my soul cheaply.
Hey. hey!
Until I die and say goodbye...
...no one can catch me.
You probably don't know
the eternal outlaws...
...who wander the distant night.