I wish you'd come here...
You'll have to excuse me.
All this talking has worn me out.
I've never seen one before!
Lain Iwakura. Are you and the Lain
of the Wired one and the same?
I've seen you before. In the Wired.
Poor Lain...
Hey, I'm Lain, aren't I?
No!
No, you're not!
That's right, Lain. You're not
needed in the real world.
I'm committing suicide!
Why? Why are you warm?
Why do I have to feel the
heat from your body?
Yes. I'm God.
How could you...?
Lain,you'd have more fun if
you were a little more sociable.
She's changed, all right.
Are you okay?
Lately... You've been slipping
back to your old self, Lain.
Are you okay? Lain, I...
Lain, I'm sorry! it's all
our fault! Are you okay, Lain?
Glad to hear it.
Are you tired?
Yes.
You're incredible...
So, you've loaded an emulator of
that Navi into your own brain.
It's dangerous to subject yourself to
that much information all at once.
At your current capacity,
you'll overflow.
Am I a machine?
Don't talk about me
like I'm a machine.
I didn't mean to.
This is basically a software problem.
Lain, you're software.
You're not hardware.
Software...?
Yes. An executable
program with a body.
Be quiet...
Be quiet!
Chisa...!
Chisa, we walked home
together just once, right?
I understand. I finally
understand what you told me.
Lain...
It's easy to die, Lain.
Right?
There's nothing easy about dying.
Sure it is!
Lain, you already have a tool
that will let you do it.
What do you-
The safety's already off.
The trigger's heavy, so hold it with
both hands and pull it with your thumb.
A girl isn't strong enough.
What, you still want to
stay in the real world?
Hey, that's not fair.
You called me here, remember?
I... I never...
Bodies are meaningless.
You're wrong.
Lain.
What is this?
I thought that maybe we could meet
after school and I could introduce you.
This guy's pretty cute!
And then those rumors about
you and that teacher...
I think if you get a boyfriend,
everyone will know they're a lie.
See you tomorrow.
We'll talk about it then.
'Bye!
It's not a lie.
W-Who's there?
Who's there?!
Lain...?
W-What?
What's happened to you...? You...
It wasn't me.
I never peeked at
your secrets, Arisu,
and I never sent those
secrets out onto the Wired.
It was you, Lain! I saw you!
That isn't me.
It looks like I'm not the only
me. Some other me did it.
What're you talking about?
You might not be the
only Arisu, either.
But no matter how often I say I didn't
do it, you'll believe that I did
So I'll make it so that
it never happened.
I've been working really hard
to be able to do that.
What do you mean?
I don't need devices anymore.
It looks like I've already
destroyed the border...
between the Wired and the real world.
I can go anyplace I want to now.
Sol came here.
I should be able to undo
something that happened!
Lain...
I...-
I'm scared...
I'm scared...!
Arisu!
Arisu! Good morning!
Good morning.
What's up, Arisu?
Why are you depressed?
Oh, is it that time of the month?
Hey, you ever hear of "delicacy"?
Come on, I was only...
Juri... I don't think I can
go through with it today.
Huh? Go through with what?
What? Didn't you send
me a CU-mail yesterday?
No, I didn't send you
anything yesterday...
You're sure acting
strange today, Arisu.
Arisu!
Oh, that teacher... He sure is hot!
Yeah! But rumor has it that
he's seeing an 8th-grader!
What, are you serious?
That's gross!
Um... Listen, I...
What is it?
A-About that teacher... and me...
ls there something between
that teacher and you?
Do you like him or something?
Sorry, you're too late!
Yeah! He already has a girlfriend.
That's not like you, Arisu.
Yeah, she sure is
acting strange today.
Lain! Good morning!
Hurry it UP!
Come on, Lain!
Lain!
Lain, you...
Lain,you smiled...
I thought I was innocent,
but I'm being punished.
I didn't start this, but I
have to finish it somehow.
I can't say I didn't know about it,
but I don't remember taking part in it.
I get the feeling my
freedom cost me dearly,
but I don't remember
selling my soul cheaply.
Hey. hey!
Until I die and say goodbye...
...no one can catch me.
You probably don't know
the eternal outlaws...
...who wander the distant night.