What are you scared of?
Just try it for a little bit.
No, that's not it.
I don't have any mail...
I don't get it...
Oh.
I thought somebody was here.
Who?
Your imaginary friend.
Or something like that.
You're gonna be late again.
Lain!
Good morning.
See what I mean?
It couldn't have been her.
You think so? But...
What?
Cut it out. I feel sorry for her.
It's nothing. Come on, let's go.
Okay.
But...
Oh, let it go.
Have you gotten any more e-mail?
E-mail?
From Chisa.
Oh, that. No, I haven't
gotten any more.
You got that prank mail, too, Lain?
What?
Really?
I was just curious.
Huh?
You know, maybe she does
look a little like her...
Lain, what were you
doing last night?
Yeah, yeah!
Come on, I'm telling
you it wasn't her!
I guess not. She doesn't
look like her at all.
What?
There was a girl at Cyberia last
night who looked just like you, Lain.
Cyberia?
We finally worked up the
nerve to go there last night.
Come on, it wasn't such a big deal.
Oh, right, you were the
one who was all nervous!
Oh. It's a club. Young
people go there at night.
There was a girl there who
looked a little like you, Lain.
Last night, I...
We know. It wasn't you.
We didn't get a good look at her,
but she had on these wild clothes,
and chewed people out left and right.
Yeah, it was like she
was your total opposite.
But she did look like her...
Hey, I know! Let's take
her with us next time!
You want to make sure, huh?
Cut it out! You're just
making fun of her.
I bet when a girl like Lain goes to
a club, her personality does a 180!
Oh. Maybe Lain would liven up a bit.
Right! Let's go, Lain!
It might be fun.
You'd have more fun if you were
a little more sociable, Lain.
Right, Lain?
Accela, a type of smart supplement,
uses nano-mechanisms to oscillate at
a specific frequency within the body,
triggering the secretion
of a specific hormone.
It is said that when secreted, this
hormone affects the time-sense...
of the human mind, making it seem
as if one's awareness is accelerated.
Not only the consciousness, but the
workings of the brain itself are altered,
multiplying the brain's operational
capacity by 2 to 12 times.
The nano-mechanism itself is destroyed
by digestive juices within 24 hours,
but it is unknown how
long its effectiveness...
Is this your place?
Great! I have a delivery for you.
I'll start unloading it.
Could you get the gate for me?
Could you sign this, please?
This thing is so cool!
I wish I had one of these...
Thanks.
All this is yours?
I'm not sure.
Then you don't know what this is?
It's a top of the line Navi!
Fully loaded, too!
With this kind of horsepower,
you can move around freely...
...without any stress at
all, even in the Wired.
I use a home-brew system, myself.
it doesn't hold a candle to this.
No, it's not like that. I don't
know anything about it, either.
You will soon enough.
Have a good one.
Your Navi came, right?
Get that mess cleaned up soon,
all right? It's in the way.
I'll set it up for you after dinner.
This Navi's good enough that
I'd want to take it for a spin.
Dad...
I want you to set it up now.
Hey, why are you in such a hurry?
Lain...
I'll do it.
You can't keep using that
children's Navi forever.
For communication, you
need a powerful system...
...that will mature alongside
your relationships with people.
Understand, Lain?
Come here.
Register yourself as
the machine's user.
Try talking to it.
Hello, Navi.
Now this Navi's yours, Lain.
You can show off to
your friends now.
Oops.
Hey, Mika. Something wrong?
Navi, do I have mail?
Lain has no mail.
Okay, turn left at that corner!
Then go straight ahead.
See it?
Yeah.
We're in the basement! Got it?
Hey! You!
You're blocking the stairs.
Sorry.
If you do it that way,
...you'll get spotted by the
Info-Guard Center right off the bat!
What's the big deal?
I'd just be attacking it.
Hey, next time we go over
to that game center, let's...
What took you so long, Lain?
You're usually in bed now,
aren't you, Lain?
Lain, don't you have anything
better to wear out at night?
We'll pick out something a little
more grown-up for you next time, Lain.
You think she'd look good
in grown-up clothes?
Reika!
Hey ...
What?
I guess the girl we saw
really wasn't Lain...
That's what I've been telling you!
Lain doesn't dress like
that or talk like that.
She doesn't look like that, either.
Did she really look like me?
Yeah! I was positive it was you!
Oh.
What the-J?!
He's got a gun!
Help me!
- Juri!
Lain!
What's she doing?
- Reika, take care of Juri.
- Arisu?
Arisu!
What're you looking at?
Lain, what're you doing?
Let's get out of here! Hurry!
Lain!
Go away!
Why are you making me do this?!
What right do you have?!
I just wanted to clear
my head, that's all!
I don't know anything about
it! Leave me out of it!
You're that scattered god's--
I don't want anything to
do with it! Nothing!
The Wired can't be allowed to
interfere with the real world!
I don't want anything to do with it!
Who the hell are you?!
L-Lain...
I don't want anything to do with it...
Don't want anything to do with it...
Don't want... I don't want... Don't
want anything to do with it...
Don't want anything to...
Don't want...
Don't want anything...
Don't want anything to do with it...
Don't want... Don't want
anything to do with it...
I don't want--
No matter where you go,
everyone's connected.
I thought I was innocent,
but I'm being punished.
I didn't start this, but I
have to finish it somehow.
I can't say I didn't know about it,
but I don't remember taking part in it.
I get the feeling my
freedom cost me dearly,
but I don't remember
selling my soul cheaply.
Hey, hey!
Until I die and say goodbye...
...no one will ever catch me.
You probably don't know
the eternal outlaws...
...who wander the distant night.