If people can connect to one another,
even the smallest voice will grow loud.
even their lives will become longer.
So...
Lain? I'm coming in.
Lain?
Thanks.
But I already verified that
register a long time ago.
That's hilarious!
Right...
I can't wait for the next-gen
protocol to come out.
When it does, I could...
Why are you guys so nice to me?
No, that's not what I think.
It's just a little strange.
I don't have many friends.
Thanks, Knights.
Yeah, right!
Connect
Hard at work studying, I see...
Listen, Lain...
It's like you're going back
to your old self lately.
Come hang out with
us again sometime.
Life's depressing when
you're alone all the time!
I know, but I'm not alone.
Huh? Who's with you, then?
Everybody comes to see me.
No, that's not right...
Maybe I go to see them.
What? The Wired, you mean?
A net-pal isn't the
same as a real friend.
Reika sure is an old fogey when
it comes to some things, huh?
Yeah, an old fogey!
So what if I am?
Anyway, Lain, what kind of sites
have you been hanging out at?
It's a secret.
Oh, acting high and mighty, huh?
Come on, tell us!
Hey, this'll look good!
No way! You should just give up!
I think this one's better.
No way! This one's better!
Right, Lain?
Hey, let's go to that store
we went to the other day.
They say they're having a 30-minute
all-you-can-eat ice cream special today.
I'm hungry!
Huh?
What? What is it?
What's with that kid?
Beats me.
Come on, let's go!
Let's go, Lain.
Lain, what's--
No way!
What is that?
What the...?
Lain? That's--
You've certainly been
coming home early lately.
Now it's Lain who's
staying out late.
Do you think you'll get that
college recommendation?
Speak of the devil.
A strange phenomenon appeared
in the skies above Tokyo today.
People in the area who observed it
report being deeply unnerved by it.
Was this a malicious prank?
Was it merely a natural phenomenon,
or was it a deliberate act?
Hello, Navi.
Hello, Lain.
Connect to Wired.
So you're Lain, huh?
You're somethin' else, to be able to
translate your real world form...
...so well here into the Wired.
Stupid Cheshire Cat wannabe...
"Wannabe," nothing. At my user
level, this is the best I can do.
Most people can only manage ears.
I'm way better than them,
don't you think?
Shut your hole. Just give
me the information.
I helped Lain... This is gonna make
me a hero with the local users.
You're more noise than signal...
Tell me about the game that all the
grade-schoolers are playing.
A game? There's all
kinds of kids' games.
Moron.
You've got a hunch that
tells you it's a game?
To a kid, anything can be a game.
So you called up
the search result...
Now I get it. This man
might know the answer.
The child-killer scientist.
You live up to your reputation, Lain!
You searched him on your own!
In the real world, he's just an old man
waiting to die in a private hospital ward.
I helped you.
A little.
Ask him about KIDS.
I already know. You're not much
of a guide, Cheshire Cat.
Now it's your turn,
Professor Hodgeson.
Tell me all about it.
You look very lifelike, young lady.
What's "KIDS"?
It's so peaceful here...
I want to relax here until my
body rots in the real world.
You know what's
happening, don't you?
What's "KIDS"?
Time passes so beautifully here...
And quietly, as if it will last forever.
Show me the experiment data from
15 years ago, Professor Hodgeson.
I never meant to put the
children in any danger.
I don't mean 15 years ago, I mean the
game that all the kids are playing now.
They're reproducing your
experiment, aren't they?
Somebody dug it out
of the trash can.
I thought I had erased all the data.
Tell me about the
Kensington Experiment.
Psi, parapsychological ability,
is present in most children,
although very faint in most.
It's nothing as outrageous as ESP.
It's just good intuition, or enough
physical ability to bend a coin.
What're these that are
attached to their heads?
We called them Outer Receptors.
That's what receives the Psi.
This is KIDS.
Individually, their Psi may be weak,
but if I could collect
their power...
What were you expecting?
Something beyond imagining.
That's what I wanted
to see, young lady.
What did you make them do?
Science isn't merely about
proving hypotheses.
That's what I believed.
That's not what I mean...!
So, you didn't give any
thought to the children.
As you say.
It was the KID System
that converted the weak...
...electromagnetic waves of the brain
received by the Outer Receptors,
...and enhanced the functions of
a specific area of the brain.
That is what KIDS really is.
When the children's Psi was combined,
how much energy was generated?
Stop it...
Enough!
I smashed KIDS to pieces so
that it could never be rebuilt.
But its schematics found
their way onto the Wired...
...and eventually
coalesced somewhere.
Someone found them.
And updated it so that
it could manifest...
...phenomena without
Outer Receptors.
If it can influence these new children
to that extent as an emulation...
...I'm forced to
acknowledge their talent.
Is that all you can think about?
You don't care about the children?
No matter how much I punish myself,
those children won't
return to the real world.
And there's even less that I can
do about this current group.
Talk about self-centered.
So who's using it now?
Young lady...
All this talking has worn me out.
It was nice meeting you.
I don't know what you plan
to do in the Wired...
or what sort of being you're
trying to become,
but you're powerful.
Incredibly powerful.
If there really is a god here in
the Wired, you're a blessed child.
I... I'm not...
I wonder where the power of the
rogues that run the KIDS emulation...
...and this other kind
of power come from?
Rogues?
If you'll excuse me, then...
I'm a little tired.
My body's time has run out.
My wish has come true.
Knights...
Shut up!
Who are you people? Why did
you try to tell me all this?
Was I just your toy?
Is this all a game?
What do you want to
use the children for?
Are you just doing it for kicks?
You'll do anything if you can do
it and if you think it'll be fun!
Then you're just
a bunch of losers!
Aren't you going to speak up?
Isn't anybody going to answer?
Them...!
Now I get it!
You!
You're Knights, right?
You are, aren't you?
Please get down.
W-What the hell was that?
The coolant system in your room.
They must've planted a parasite
bomb in your coolant system.
It almost sounds like you're
saying you didn't do it.
It wasn't us.
Who was it, then?
Who did it?!
The Knights.
I thought I was innocent,
but I'm being punished.
I didn't start this, but I
have to finish it somehow.
I can't say I didn't know about it,
but I don't remember taking part in it.
I get the feeling my
freedom cost me dearly,
but I don't remember
selling my soul cheaply.
Hey, hey!
Until I die and say goodbye...
... no one can catch me.
You probably don't know
the eternal outlaws...
...who wander the distant night.